# CHRIS LEE



axiom88guru@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/chris-lee-434a831b9



+18506332053



https://github.com/codechef703

## Summary

I am a programmer all of my life, since my 19, learning by myself primarily.

Now I am focused on Blockchain technology using Web3/Solidity as well as web/mobile programming using Node.js/React.js/Ruby on Rails.

Many projects I have done as a full-stack developer because when it's small or medium, I can provide fast pace and clean result.

I like a positive or neutral emotional state in working, I like clearly defined goals. When it's not well decided, I often can provide my expertness in web-development to help a customer choose a set of features, or make more effective infrastructure.

# **Experience**



### ເວັດ Freelance Software Engineer

#### Upwork

Mar 2010 - Present (12 years 4 months +)

- -Developed responsive web applications with frontend \* backend framework options(HTML, CSS,
- Javascript, jQuery, Typescript, Angular, React, Vue, Ruby/Ruby on Rails, Node.js/Express, PHP/ Laravel/WordPress)
- -Developed cutting-edge/robust mobile applications using React Native, Flutter
- -Built +15 websites & +5 mobile applications for 10 to 15 individual clients and startups

# Blockchain Developer (Web3/Solidity/SmartContracts) - Remote

#### HedgePay

Aug 2020 - Mar 2022 (1 year 8 months)

- -Contributed to develop a new DeFi system called HedgePay.
- -Implemented various cryptocurrency functions of HedgePay
- -invest, reward, transfer, swap and so on.
- -Created a new stable coin called HedgeCoin
- -Updated the system to be used in multi network.
- -Built structured front end using React hooks and Redux toolkit



# 🔝 Software Engineer (Ruby, Node.js, React, React Native) - Remote

#### 1ST NATIONS MORTGAGE CORPORATION

Apr 2020 - Nov 2021 (1 year 8 months)

- \*Maintained multiple live websites & mobile apps developed using Ruby and Node.js, React.js and ReactNative
- \*Ensured that all websites are bug-free and easy to use.

# Software Engineer II (Ruby on Rails) - Remote

# TourMega

Apr 2018 - Feb 2020 (1 year 11 months)

- -Developed a search engine dedicated to tours and activities around the world.
- -Integrated Google Maps api, Stripe payment gateway, Facebook apis
- -Developed admin dashboard to manage users, bookings
- -Developed a messaging app using Socket.io



# MERN Stack Developer (Node.js/MongoDB/React) - Remote

#### Legably

Aug 2017 - Mar 2018 (8 months)

Developed a job market platform in Node.js with MongoDB and React.js.

Created the "Payment Integration" using Chargebee

Integrated Stripe API to make payments

Developed admin dashboard to manage users, projects

Developed a messaging app using Socket.io



### Software Engineer (Ruby on Rails) - Remote

#### CoinFalcon

May 2016 - Jun 2017 (1 year 2 months)

Served as the RoR front-end developer for the front-end development of the coinfalcon.com website launched in early 2016.

The build system itself was developed in Ruby and used a listener thread to pull jobs from the PostgreSQL database when they were entered from the website. The website was a full-stack application built on Ruby on Rails and ES2016

## Full-stack Software Engineer - Remote

#### Almosafer

Feb 2014 - Jan 2016 (2 years)

- -Built the first generation of Almosafer website & mobile iOS/Android app
- -Served as the architect and technical lead for the front-end development of the Almosafer hotel booking website & mobile application in early 2014.

#### Freelance Frontend Developer

#### Upwork

Mar 2010 - Apr 2014 (4 years 2 months)

- -Learned fron-end technogical options (HTML, CSS, Javascript, and more)
- -Developed responsive web applications with Javascript and AngularJS
- -Built +10 various websites like Ecommerce, Social Dating, Productivity, Real Estate, Education businesses for 10 to 15 individual clients and startups

#### **Education**



### Osaka University

Information Technology Mar 2009 - Jan 2010

## MALAYSIA-JAPAN INTERNATIONAL INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY (MJIIT)

# Non Degree Program, Information Technology

Feb 2007 - Jan 2009

# **Skills**

web3.js • Solidity • Smart Contracts • Blockchain • Stripe Connect • ECMAScript • Ruby on Rails • Node.js • React.js • Databases